export const questions = [
  {
    question: "What is React?",
    options: [
      "CSS framework",
      "React Library",
      "React Framework",
      "Testing tool",
    ],
    answer: "React Library",
  },
  {
    question: "Which company developed React?",
    options: ["Google", "Facebook", "Microsoft", "Amazon"],
    answer: "Facebook",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the command to create a new React app?",
    options: [
      "npx create-react-app",
      "npm install react",
      "npx init-react",
      "npm start react-app",
    ],
    answer: "npx create-react-app",
  },
  {
    question: "Which hook is used to handle state in functional components?",
    options: ["useEffect", "useState", "useReducer", "useMemo"],
    answer: "useState",
  },
  {
    question: "How can you pass data from a parent to a child component?",
    options: ["State", "Props", "Events", "Functions"],
    answer: "Props",
  },
  {
    question: "Which hook is used to handle side effects in React?",
    options: ["useState", "useContext", "useEffect", "useMemo"],
    answer: "useEffect",
  },
  {
    question: "What is JSX?",
    options: [
      "JavaScript XML",
      "Java Syntax Extension",
      "JavaScript Syntax Extension",
      "JavaScript XHTML",
    ],
    answer: "JavaScript XML",
  },
  {
    question: "Which method is used to render React content into the DOM?",
    options: [
      "React.render()",
      "ReactDOM.render()",
      "renderDOM()",
      "React.create()",
    ],
    answer: "ReactDOM.render()",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'key' prop help with in React lists?",
    options: [
      "Identifying the order of items",
      "Optimizing performance",
      "Storing element data",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Optimizing performance",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not a lifecycle method in React?",
    options: [
      "componentDidMount",
      "componentWillUnmount",
      "shouldComponentUpdate",
      "componentWillLoad",
    ],
    answer: "componentWillLoad",
  },
];
